<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2016 Richard Hughes <richard@hughsie.com> -->
<component type="driver">
  <id>com.nvidia.driver</id>
  <name>NVIDIA Linux Graphics Driver</name>
  <summary>Accelerated Linux Graphics Driver</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      The NVIDIA Accelerated Linux Graphics Driver brings accelerated 2D
      functionality and high-performance OpenGL support to Linux with the
      use of NVIDIA graphics processing units.
    </p>
    <p>
      These drivers provide optimized hardware acceleration for OpenGL and X
      applications and support nearly all recent NVIDIA GPU products.
      The NVIDIA graphics driver uses a Unified Driver Architecture: the single
      graphics driver supports all modern NVIDIA GPUs.
    </p>
  </description>
  <translation/>
  <url type="homepage">http://www.nvidia.com/</url>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>LicenseRef-proprietary:NVIDIA</project_license>
  <developer_name>NVIDIA Corporation</developer_name>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>NVIDIA</keyword>
    <keyword>driver</keyword>
    <keyword>GeForce</keyword>
    <keyword>CUDA</keyword>
    <keyword>Quadro</keyword>
    <keyword>Vulkan</keyword>
    <keyword>OpenGL</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <update_contact>negativo17@gmail.com</update_contact>
  <suggests>
    <id>nvidia-settings.desktop</id>
  </suggests>
  <releases>
    <release date="2016-09-08" version="370.28">
      <description>
        <p>
          New short lived branch release.
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>Improved compatibility with recent Linux kernels.</li>
          <li>Fixed undefined symbol references in libnvidia-glcore.so.</li>
          <li>Fixed a potential hang in Vulkan applications such as vkQuake and DOTA2 that use vkFences for present synchronization.</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug that caused the driver to not set HDMI YUV 420 4K modes correctly on some TVs, such as the VIZIO D40u-D1.</li>
          <li>Updated CurrentMetaMode reporting via the NV-CONTROL API to reflect whether ForceCompositionPipeline or ForceFullCompositionPipeline are set in the current MetaMode.</li>
          <li>Added the ability to over- and under-clock certain GeForce GPUs in the GeForce GTX 1000 series and later. For GPUs that allow it, an offset can be applied to clock values in some clock domains of all performance levels. This clock manipulation is done at the user's own risk. See the README documentation of the "CoolBits" X configuration option for more details.</li>
          <li>Implemented initial support for PRIME Synchronization to synchronize flipping between an NVIDIA PRIME display source and a separate PRIME display sink. This support is experimental and currently requires a prerelease X.org X server.</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug that prevented Vulkan applications from presenting from multiple queues to the same X11 swapchain.</li>
          <li>Added the "PixelShiftMode" MetaMode option, enabling support for 4K and 8K pixel shift displays. See the README for details.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2016-08-23" version="367.44">
      <description>
        <p>
          Added support for the following GPU:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>TITAN X (Pascal)</li>
          <li>GeForce GTX 1060 6GB</li>
          <li>GeForce GTX 1060 3GB</li>
        </ul>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed a regression that caused applications using indirect GLX to crash.</li>
          <li>Fixed a regression introduced in 367.35 that caused the first modeset of the X server to display blank if the features requested in the X configuration file enabled the X driver's composition pipeline. This would be triggered, e.g., by MetaMode tokens such as ForceCompositionPipeline, ForceFullCompositionPipeline, Rotation, Reflection, and Transform.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release date="2016-07-15" version="367.35">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed a regression that could cause console corruption when resuming from suspend.</li>
          <li>Improved buffer write performance of the nvidia-drm DRM KMS driver by using write-combined DRM Dumb Buffers where available.</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug that caused X to crash when applying changes to the RandR CscMatrix property while VT-switched away from X.</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug that caused a crash when exiting nvidia-settings on displays with 8 or 15 bit color depths.</li>
          <li>Added support for VDPAU Feature Set H to the NVIDIA VDPAU driver. GPUs with VDPAU Feature Set H are capable of hardware-accelerated decoding of 8192x8192 (8k) H.265/HEVC video streams.</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug that caused the X server to sometimes skip displaying Vulkan frames when the Composite extension is enabled.</li>
          <li>Added support for querying clock values on Pascal GPUs.</li>
          <li>Removed the Base Mosaic configuration option from nvidia-settings on systems where the feature is not actually supported.</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug that caused nvidia-smi to report an inaccurate version number.</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug that could lead to a system crash if there was a peer-to-peer mapping still active during CUDA context teardown.</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug that prevented nvidia-bug-report.sh from finding relevant messages in kernel log files.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
